Jason Coello

New York, NY 10025 | E: jasoncoellox@gmail.com

Summary

Versatile, reliable and competent software engineer with over 8 years of experience in Full Stack Web Development (SaaS App, SPA, PWA, Decentralized App, Real-time App, Admin Dashboard, Browser Extension), Hybrid / Native Mobile App Development, Functional Programming, OOP, Database Administration / Design, Data Visualization, and RESTful API Development / Integration.

Skills

- Application development
- Advanced knowledge of embedded systems
- Interface design and implementation
- Agile development methodologies
- Amazon Web Services
- Web development tools
- Enterprise Technology

- Advanced retouching
- Technical support
- Administrative support
- Quality assurance
- Databases
- UI updates
- Website analytics tools

Experience

FRONT END DEVELOPER | 07/2019 to 09/2019

Nai Partners

- Coordinated system installations, testing and code corrections.
- Collaborated closely with Nai Partners to keep projects on track and meet anticipated deadlines.
- Worked closely with other development team members to identify and remove software bugs.
- Directed all software design, architecture and programming.

INTERN ARCHITECT | 09/2019 to 10/2019

Medpricer.Com Inc.

• Expanded systems with new features and structural components.

LEAD DEVELOPER | 09/2019 to 09/2019

Fantasy Football Blueprint

- Designed software databases.
- Implemented and tested enhancement feature requests to improve product functionality and extend performance.
- Collected and defined customer requirements to produce product scopes.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | 10/2019 to 12/2019

Ramboll Shair

- Evaluated software development project plans and recommended adjustments.
- Optimized system performance by making proactive adjustments and resolving bugs.
- Coordinated system installations, testing and code corrections.
- Created proof-of-concept prototype applications for demonstration and evaluation purposes.

BACKEND DEVELOPER | 07/2019 to 09/2019

AmericanFlat

- Tested and resolved problems with software functionality and recommended improvements to applications.
- Coded, tested and developed solutions in alignment with project requirements.

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER | 05/2019 to Current Relovy

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER | 07/2019 to Current

GoPrep

- Troubleshot, tested and remedied identified issues before software deployment.
- Redesigned sites to enhance navigation and improve visual appeal.
- Supported special projects upon request from the department manager.

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER | 12/2019 to Current Waft

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER | 12/2019 to Current **123ConsultingSolutions**

U.S ARMY COMBAT ENGINEER - CRESTVIEW, FL | 04/2009 to 04/2015

Primary Husky Mounted Detection System (HDMS) Operator

- Dedicated team member, strived to learn and test the capabilities and weakness of the HMDS in various terrains and soil compositions, in order to ensure the mission continued.
- Bronze Star (V device) nominee and lead locator for highest number of improvised explosive devices (IEDs) found during off-road operations in Afghanistan using ground penetrating radar (GPR).
- Managed and accounted for over \$6 million dollars in ground-penetrating radar/mine detection equipment.
- Operated in over 60 counter-landmine missions, 6,000 km of route cleared, and provided freedom of movement for >1 million third country nationals and Special Forces members.
- Provided training to numerous junior members, which greatly enhanced the knowledge and competence of the route clearance patrol.

Education and Training

New York University - New York, NY | Bachelor of Science 2015

Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

- http://jasoncoello.com
- https://github.com/jasoncoello